Hello
everyone, and welcome to another episode of Trust Talks.
Today we are going to discuss a
detailed comparison of two recently launched health insurance plans
.  One is the Elevate plan from ICCI Leopards
, and the other is the Medicare Select plan from Tata AG General
Insurance Company
.  About the Company Top
USP of this Plan Inbuilt
Features and Optional Riders and the
Most Important To understand in detail
which plan has lower premium etc. in these two plans,
try to watch the video in full without missing it.
Before going into the video, let's start with an
introduction About myself
My name is Sanoj Lal, a certified
financial consultant, working in the
insurance and investment
industry for the last 19 years.
We bring all the news related to insurance to you only after studying and researching it thoroughly. If
you have not subscribed to this channel called Truststock yet,
please
subscribe to the channel to get the right information at the right time to be healthy
and wealthy.
About the Company ICICI Bank, Tata Motors and Tata AG do not need a big introduction. They are in the top
five positions of Indian general insurance companies.  The following are the two general
insurance companies. Both of them are health
insurance companies. The advantage of choosing general insurance companies is their
good claim
settlement track record.
In 2023, ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Company's ICR was
78.85% while
Tata AG General Insurance Company's ICR was
77.94%.
ICR indicates how much of the total premium collected by an insurance company in a year was paid as insurance claims.
Insurance
companies that maintain an ICR between 60 percent and 80 percent can be considered as companies that maintain a good claim settlement
track record. Although there are
many
in-built features and optional riders
available in both these plans, we are going to discuss the
three most important features of these.
Top Three USBs of This
Plan ICI Lombard's Elevate
plan is the first USB. Infinity
Care, as the name suggests, is an infinite coverage.  In
the case of hospitalization, if there is
an unlimited expense claim outside the sum insured of the customer,
through this feature, the customer
gets insurance coverage for this.
This feature works out only once for the customer during the entire policy period. The second
USB is the power booster.
Through this feature, the customer gets 100% of the base ammunshed every year
as a loyalty bonus.
For example,
a person with a base sum insured of Rs. 10 lakhs gets an additional
coverage of Rs. 10 lakhs next year.
After 5 years, this plan has a
sum insured coverage of up to Rs. 1 crore.
This is for unlimited time. Whether there is a claim or
not, the USP of the
guarantee is the unlimited sum. It is
very simple.
You can decide the sum insured coverage you want. For example, if
you need a high sum insured coverage,
for example, if you
need an insurance sum of Rs. 10 crores or an insurance sum of Rs. 10 crores, then through this feature, you can
get insurance coverage for that.
Next, let us understand the
top three USPs of the Tata Medicare Select plan. The
first USP is
Infinity Advantage and the
Infinity Care of the ICICI Elevate plan. The
same feature is being worked out
here as well. Infinite
insurance coverage is available throughout the entire policy period. The second important USP
is Early Access. If a customer chooses a
two-
year or three-year multi-year policy instead of a single-year
policy, the total cumulative base sum assured that the customer gets in
two years or three years
can be utilized through this feature at any time during the entire policy period of the customer.
For example,
a person choosing a Rs. 10 lakh based mensured three-year multi-year policy will get
cumulatively in that policy in three years.
10 Lakhs and third year 10 Lakhs,
so the total is 30 Lakhs.
In case the customer makes a claim of 20 Lakhs in the first year itself,
through this Early Access feature, the customer
gets insurance coverage of 20 Lakhs. USB is the same as the
Power Booster feature in the Super Recharge Elevate plan, and
100% sum insured is
guaranteed through this feature
.  This feature provides
three times of base sum insured for sum
insured up to 5 lakhs and five times of sum insured for sum insured above 10 lakhs.
Next, let us understand the eligibility criteria to
join these two plans. The first
point is the policy type.
Individual and
floater options are available in both the plans. The next
point is the family definition. In the Medicare
Select plan,
we can enroll up to seven members in the floater option, while in the
Elevate
plan, we can join a maximum of two adults and three
children. The age criteria in the
Select plan
states that the limit is 18 years for adults and 25 years for children. In the
Elevate plan, adults can enroll up to 18
years and children up to 30 years in this plan.  You can
enroll in the next
point sum insured limit in the Select
plan, which is up to 5 lakhs. The
sum insured limit is said to be up to
5 lakhs to unlimited in the Elevate plan. The
next point policy term is one year to three years or multi-year policy. Although it is possible to opt for Medicare Select in the Elevate plan, it is up to one year to five years. The customer chooses the policy time. Next, the inbuilt features of this plan are the
basic features that we are
going to discuss. The first
point is room rent. In both the
plans, there is a single private AC room. What is
offered in this is the
next point pre and post
hospitalization. In the Select plan, the
pre and post hospitalization is 9 to 90 days, in the
Elevate plan,
it is 90 or 180 days.
Important features like AYUSH
Benefit Donor Expenses, Domiciliary
Hospitalization, Day Care Procedures and
Most Important Modern
Treatment are covered up to the same extent in both the plans. The
next point
is the Restoration Facility which is insured up to 100% of the base in
both the plans. This too can be worked
out as an unlimited time Restoration Facility.  The next
point is ambulance cover. Both
plans cover ambulance expenses. The
next important
point is the no claim bonus. In the Elevate
plan, the no claim bonus comes
as a guarantee that is 20% of the
sum insured up to 100%. In the Medical
Select plan, it is 50% every
year. Every claim is
free. Next, the
optional riders of this plan are the features that the customer
needs. Optional riders are the features that
we purchase by paying additional premium. Let
us understand the important optional riders of these two plans. The
first important
optional rider is the consumables or non-
medical expenses. In both the plans,
it
covers the expenses up to the sum insured. The second
point is the infinity cover. As already discussed, infinite
insurance
coverage is provided in the entire policy at one time.  If it is
available through the Infinite Advantage feature in Medical Select, then in the Elevate plan,
it
is worked out as Infinity Care. The next point is the
loyalty bonus. In the Select
plan, it is worked out as a super charge bonus. For
sum insured up to 5 lakhs, the customer gets three times coverage and for
sum insured above 10 lakhs, it is worked out
as a
loyalty bonus. The Power Booster benefit is a loyalty bonus that is worked out in Elevate, which is
unlimited time. The next important point is Maternity. Maternity expenses can be claimed up to
10 times of base amount in both plans. Expenses up to one lakh can be
claimed in this. The
next point is
Pre-exit disease weight loss period reduction.
This option is not available in the Medical Select plan.  In the Elevate
plan, the option to reduce the waiting period for diseases such as asthma,
hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidemia, obesity by
30 days is
available through Jump Start. Next, the
waiting periods of these two plans are:
Initial waiting period is 30 days Specified disease waiting period
is 24 months and Pre-existing disease waiting period is
normally three
years. Maternity is two years in these two plans. The waiting
period is said to be one year.
The option to reduce the waiting period for maternity
is available in both these plans.
Next, we will discuss the most important
point, the premium comparison of these two plans
.
Here is an illustration of a family of four, aged 32-29, with a sum insured of Rs. 10 lakh plus an optional rider and non-medical expenses added on.  If you
choose the Medicare Select plan, the annual premium for this
family
is 13638 rupees. If you choose the Elevate
plan, the premium is
rupees per year. I think you all understand the comparison between the
Elevate plan of ICCI Lombard and the
Medicare Select plan of Tata AG that we discussed today to some
extent. If you want to
know more about this plan and
need a detailed consultation,
you can call or WhatsApp on the number provided
.
Before the video ends, let me
remind you that insurance is a subject matter of
solicitation.
Before choosing any insurance product, read and understand the
terms and conditions of that product
clearly.
Similarly, if you have not yet subscribed to this channel called Trustok,
please subscribe to the
channel to get the right information at the right time. I am
coming with another informative video, I am signing
of Sanoj
[Music]